nissan.ca 2018-10-29

# Nissan Privacy Policy | Nissan Canada

Last updated: May 3, 2017

Nissan respects your privacy and is committed to protecting it. Any Personal Information gathered by Nissan Canada Inc., Nissan Canada Financial Services Inc., including their division Nissan Canada Finance, and Nissan Canada Extended Services Inc. (collectively, **“Nissan”** ) will only be used by Nissan, its affiliates, dealers, or any organization authorized by Nissan, in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy, including for the purposes of enhancing your Nissan experience in providing you with Nissan products, services and information. By using Nissan websites or otherwise providing your Personal Information to Nissan, you agree to the collection, use and disclosure of your Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

If you do not agree with this Privacy Policy, please do not use our websites, or provide any Personal Information to Nissan.

  1. Objective & Scope of Policy
  2. The Collection, Use & Disclosure of Personal Information
  3. Accuracy
  4. Retention
  5. Security
  6. Visiting Nissan Websites
  7. Information for Subscribers to NissanConnect services
  8. Accessing and Correcting Personal Information
  9. Opting out of Marketing Promotions
  10. Amendments to this Policy
  11. Nissan Dealers
  12. Contact Us

**1\. Objective & Scope of Policy**

Nissan is committed to respecting your privacy and has prepared this Privacy Policy to explain to you our policies and practices regarding Nissan’s collection, use and disclosure of Personal Information. 

This Privacy Policy governs Personal Information collected from and about individuals who are or may become Nissan customers and individuals who visit a Nissan website or otherwise provide their Personal Information to Nissan.

Using contractual or other arrangements, Nissan shall ensure that agents, contractors or third party service providers, who may receive Personal Information in the course of providing services to Nissan as part of our delivery of products and services, are required to protect that Personal Information in a manner consistent with this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy does not apply to Nissan’s collection of aggregate, anonymous information (information which does not identify and cannot be used to determine the identity of any individual). Nissan may use aggregate, anonymous information for any purpose permitted by law.

For quality assurance purposes, we may monitor and record calls to our customer service department.

**2\. The Collection, Use & Disclosure of Personal Information**

Nissan collects various types of information from or about you and your vehicle such as: your name, address, telephone/cellphone number, email address, title, language preferences, age, education, occupation, marital and/or family status, VIN, and credit history and financial information when you entered into a lease or loan contract.

For the purposes of this Privacy Policy "Personal Information" means any information about an identified individual, or an individual whose identity may be inferred or determined from such information.

**Nissan collects Personal Information from you in a number of different ways:**

  * Directly from you, for example, when you complete a survey, participate in a contest or event, when you enter into a lease or loan contract with Nissan or an affiliate and/or you purchase other products and services from Nissan or an affiliate, such as an extended services plan.
  * When you visit a Nissan website.
  * From our dealers, for example, when you purchase or lease a Nissan vehicle, service your vehicle or take a test drive.
  * From organizations that are partners in promotional activities such as contests and marketing and/or promotional events through which we may obtain your Personal Information with your consent. The use of your Personal Information by these organizations is governed by their privacy policy.
  * From credit bureaus and consumer reporting agencies when you apply to enter a into a lease or loan contract.
  * From vendors who provide lists of names and addresses, where you have provided your consent, to send marketing and promotional materials or other information about our products and services. The use of your Personal Information by these vendors is governed by their privacy policy.

Nissan does not knowingly collect Personal Information from anyone under the age of majority in their jurisdiction of residence, and does not use such information if Nissan discovers that it has been provided by a minor. If a child has already provided us with Personal Information, his or her parent or guardian may contact us for the purpose of deleting this information.

**Nissan may use and disclose your Personal Information to:**

  * manage our relationship with you, including to facilitate, complete or confirm any transaction or purchase of goods or services you choose to enter with us, including warranty coverage;
  * provide you with offers, incentives, marketing and/or promotional materials such as brochures and special offers, and other information about Nissan and its products and services and the products and services offered by a third party;
  * evaluate your application for a lease or loan contract, and if you are approved, to administer and manage your account, including without limitation, for the purposes of credit reporting;
  * manage your purchase, lease or loan contract, including, reviewing credit applications, evaluating your credit and conducting initial and periodic credit checks;
  * operate our websites in accordance with their terms and conditions;
  * collect amounts owing to Nissan, which may include realizing security interests in vehicles;
  * manage Nissan's relationship with its dealers;
  * improve Nissan’s products and services;
  * administer any extended service plan benefits and services;
  * conduct customer surveys and participate in market research studies conducted by organizations on behalf of Nissan;
  * conduct promotional activities including contests;
  * respond to your questions, or provide you with information or materials you have requested;
  * meet any legal or regulatory requirements, including notifying you of any product recalls or notices, or as otherwise permitted or required by applicable law; and
  * such other purposes consistent with the foregoing purposes or which are disclosed to you and to which you consent.

Your Personal Information may be disclosed or transferred to another company in the event of a transfer, change of ownership or assignment of all or part of Nissan or its assets or shares. This will occur only if the parties have entered into an agreement under which the collection, use and disclosure of Personal Information is restricted to those purposes that relate to the business transaction, including a determination of whether or not to proceed with the business transaction, and is to be used by the parties to carry out and complete the business transaction.

Nissan may disclose your Personal Information to service providers, suppliers, vendors, contractors or agents that perform services, such as marketing and advertising campaigns, customer service and data hosting, on behalf of Nissan. Personal Information will only be provided to these organizations for the purposes described in this Privacy Policy.

Nissan may also disclose your Personal Information to other third parties, for example, partners in promotional activities such as contests and marketing and/or promotional events. Personal Information will only be provided to these organizations in accordance with this Privacy Policy. The use of your Personal Information by these organizations is governed by their privacy policy.

Please note that there are circumstances where Nissan may use and/or disclose your Personal Information without your consent, such as when disclosure:

  * is permitted or required by law, court order, administrative agency or other governmental tribunal;
  * is necessary to protect the rights, privacy, safety or property of an identifiable person or group;
  * is necessary to establish or collect monies owing to Nissan;
  * is necessary to permit Nissan to pursue available remedies or limit any damages that Nissan may sustain; or
  * the information is publically available in accordance with the applicable law.

Nissan will not disclose more Personal Information than is required for the purpose of the disclosure.

**3\. Accuracy**

Nissan endeavors to ensure that any Personal Information in its control is as accurate, current and complete as necessary for the purposes for which Nissan uses or discloses that Personal Information.

**4\. Retention**

Nissan retains Personal Information as long as Nissan believes it is necessary to fulfill the purpose for which it was collected. Currently, Nissan holds Personal Information in Mississauga, Ontario; Denver, Colorado; and Sterling, VA. Nissan has in place a Records Retention Policy which outlines the procedures for the retention and subsequent disposition of Nissan records including those records that contain Personal Information.

Personal Information held by Nissan may be stored or hosted on servers in other countries, including the United States and, as a result, the governments, courts, law enforcement or regulatory agencies may require disclosure of your personal information without your consent under the applicable laws of such countries, including the USA Patriot Act.

**5\. Security**

Nissan endeavors to maintain adequate physical, procedural and technical security with respect to its offices and information storage facilities so as to help prevent any loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, or modification of Personal Information.

When our credit application asks users to enter Personal Information, we use “Secure Socket Layers (“SSL”)” encryption technology to help safeguard your Personal Information.

Nissan further protects Personal Information by restricting access to it only to those employees and service providers that have a business need to know it to carry out the purposes indicated above, or such other purposes as may be permitted or required by the applicable law. Nissan has a policy under which employee misuse of Personal Information is treated as a serious offence for which disciplinary action may be taken.

**6\. Visiting Nissan Websites**

By using Nissan websites and providing your Personal Information, you agree to the collection and use of your Personal Information in accordance with this Privacy Policy. In addition, Nissan may use third party providers to collect and record data on the use and performance of a Nissan website during your visit or your interactions with our content, ( **“Usage Data”** ), which may include and it’s not limited to: the pages you view, the search terms you enter, your IP address, whether you open emails you receive from us, your interactions with our advertisements, and Personal Information that you submit through the website. Usage Data may be collected by Nissan or its third party providers through “cookies”, log files, pixel tags, beacons, and other technology. Nissan uses this information to administer its websites, to determine the effectiveness of our advertising, and improve the services, advertising, and materials provided or displayed to you. Nissan may share information collected through its websites with suppliers to provide services for us or as permitted or required by law. Nissan may also share Usage Data in an aggregate, anonymous statistical format with third parties; such statistics would not include Personal Information.

Nissan does not respond to “do not track” beacons or other such signals.

**"Cookies"** Click here to see our Cookie Policy

Nissan also maintains standard web logs that record data about all visitors to its websites. These logs may contain the:

  * IP address assigned to your computer;
  * type of browser operating system you are using;
  * date and time you visited our websites;
  * pages you viewed on our websites;
  * address of the website from which you linked to our website;
  * Device utilized.

Nissan uses web logs and clickstream information to help us design and improve our websites, to identify popular site features and to make the sites more useful for visitors. Web logs are recorded in sequential files, and we normally do not attempt to identify individuals from these logs. However, we may use web logs to identify persons trying to break into, disrupt, or damage our website(s) or user experience or as permitted or required by applicable laws.

**Interest-Based/Online Behavioural Advertising**

Nissan may use third party service providers, including advertising networks, publishers, media companies, and social media sites, to serve Nissan advertising on our own websites, and on other non-Nissan websites, including social media sites, and Nissan may share personal information with third parties for this purpose. Such third parties may use cookies to collect information about your visits to those websites, and may set and access cookies when you visit Nissan websites. Information collected may include the pages you visited, date and time, location (if enabled), browser information and/or IP address. We may use this information to serve you with ads that we believe may be of interest to you. For example, if you visit one of our websites, you may later see our advertising on other third party sites. We normally make no attempt to link this information to you personally, except as set out in this policy. This information is gathered in order to help us customize and target our advertising to the needs and interest of our customers both on Nissan’s own websites and on third party websites, including social media platforms. This is referred to as “Interest-Based Advertising”.

**Third Party Websites**

Nissan’s website may contain links to other websites such as Facebook, Twitter, Instagram and YouTube. Nissan is not responsible for how these third party websites collect, use, or disclose your Personal Information. You should review the privacy policies/statements of all the websites you visit for information about how they handle your Personal Information.

**7\. Information for Subscribers to NissanConnect Services**

Nissan collects information from you and your Nissan vehicle. By activating, registering, subscribing, or using any of the NissanConnect services, including NissanConnectSM services powered by SiriusXM®, you consent to Nissan recording and using certain information for various purposes as more specifically described below, including without limitation, product evaluation and research and development in connection with the operation of your vehicle. NissanConnect Services powered by SiriusXM is provided to you by SXM CVS Canada Inc. For additional details regarding the collection, use and sharing of personal and vehicle information by Nissan and SiriusXM in relation to NissanConnect Services, please read the NissanConnect Services Privacy Policy available at [http://services.canada.nissanconnect.com/subscriber/privacy_policy_caen.](http://services.canada.nissanconnect.com/subscriber/privacy_policy_caen) Your vehicle is equipped with hardware and software used to facilitate collection and use of certain data described in this Privacy Policy.

**Information we collect through NissanConnect Services:** We collect information about you and your vehicle several different ways: (i) from what you and the dealer provide to us when you use NissanConnect services during a trial period or demonstration mode, subscribe to NissanConnect services, or buy or lease a Nissan vehicle; (ii) from your use of your vehicle; (iii) from calls or emails between us or our third party service providers; (iv) from our wireless or satellite carriers; and (v) from the vehicle itself.

The vehicle and driving information we may obtain from the vehicle includes, without limitation, (a) information about the vehicle and its operation, including without limitation, Vehicle Identification Number, GPS and navigation information, speed and distance information, driving habit and style, battery use management information, battery charging history1, battery deterioration information1, electrical system functions1, diagnostic trouble codes, maintenance conditions, software version information, and other data to assist in identifying and analyzing the performance of the vehicle; (b) information about your use of the vehicle and any corresponding services, websites and smartphone applications; and (c) data about accidents involving the vehicle (for example, the direction from which the vehicle was hit and which air bags have deployed).

* * *

1 Exclusive to the Nissan LEAF™

**Use and Sharing of Information for NissanConnect Services**

We may use the information we collect, and provide such information to applicable third party service providers or to any emergency contact designated by you to: (i) provide certain services to you or your vehicle (including, but not limited to, sharing that information with roadside assistance providers, emergency service providers, or others, as needed as part of our delivery of services); (ii) perform an analysis of service usage and maintenance conditions; (iii) communicate with you about your account; (iv) analyze the vehicle performance, and combine with and compare to data gathered from other Nissan vehicle owners in order to be able to determine aggregate product usage; (v) help you maintain the vehicle; (vi) evaluate and improve vehicle quality and any services related to the vehicle; (vii) prevent fraud or misuse of your vehicle or any related services; (viii) comply with all laws, regulations, and court orders; (ix) protect the rights, property, or safety of Nissan, you or others; (x) offer you new or additional products or services; or, (xi) perform market research; or, (xii) for purposes of processing the information collected.

For quality assurance purposes, we may monitor and record conversations between our respective response centres and the vehicle occupants. We may also monitor and record any calls coming into our response centres from any source.

**For NissanConnect Services or CARWINGS/NissanConnect EV equipped vehicles only**

In addition, you will be required to acknowledge, via a pop-up consent statement presented on the navigation screen of the Nissan LEAF, that the Nissan LEAF transmits recorded vehicle data to Nissan. If you click on the “Decline” button, certain information and data may not be available for your use. Some collection and sharing practices are tied to the telematics services we offer. By declining and stopping the collecting and sharing of some information, you are willing to accept limited functionality of the telematics services. Please note that even if you choose to decline, some limited vehicle data may still be collected to improve vehicle quality and any services related to the vehicle.

**Updating your account information**

It is your obligation to correct or update the subscription information provided when you subscribe to NissanConnect or CARWINGS services or when that information changes. If you do not notify us of a sale or transfer of your vehicle, we may continue to send reports or other information about the vehicle or the account to the address currently on file with us and/or new owner. In such case, we are not responsible for any privacy loss and/or related damages you may suffer.

You may update this information by calling NissanConnect service support at [1-844-543-3782](tel:1-844-543-3782) or updating online at [https://Canada.NissanConnect.com.](https://canada.nissanconnect.com/)

**Related privacy policies**

These services, and the NissanConnect mobile app, are provided to you by SXM CVS Canada Inc. and are governed by their own privacy policy and terms of service that should be read together with this Privacy Policy. Other third party service providers needed for delivery of the services, such as those companies that provide wireless services, and satellite radio services, also have their own privacy policies. Those privacy policies and subscriber terms and conditions are separate from this Privacy Policy and you should refer to these for more details and how your information is collected, used, and shared.

**8\. Accessing and Correcting Personal information**

You can review, correct or update some of your Personal Information by contacting customer service - see “Contact Us” below. The type of information available through customer service includes your name, address, telephone/cellphone number, vehicle information and previous contact with customer service. If you wish to request additional information, please send your request to the attention of our Privacy Officer. Nissan will require sufficient personal information to verify your identity and the details about the personal information you are interested in before processing your request. Where information will be disclosed, Nissan will endeavor to respond to your request within a reasonable time.

Nissan will not be able to provide you with access to information that is exempt from disclosure such as: the Personal Information of another individual, commercial proprietary information and information that is subject to solicitor-client or litigation privilege.

**9\. Opting out of Marketing Promotions**

You can unsubscribe from Nissan’s marketing promotions by either unsubscribing to our marketing emails, or by contacting customer service – see “Contact Us” below for other marketing communications. When you withdraw your consent you may no longer receive information on services and products that may be of value to you, including information relating to your NissanConnect Services. Nissan will retain Personal Information if it is required by law, to meet our contractual obligations such as honoring your warranty.

**10\. Amendments to this Policy**

This Privacy Policy is effective May 3, 2017. Nissan may need to update this Privacy Policy from time to time as our business and services change. If we do, we will post the new Privacy Policy on our website. You should check for updates to make sure you are aware of the most current Privacy Policy. We will use, share and disclose all Personal Information in accordance with the Privacy Policy in effect at the time the Personal Information was collected, unless you provide us with further consent.

**11\. Nissan Dealers**

Nissan dealers are independently owned legal entities separate from Nissan. You should refer to your Nissan dealer’s privacy statement/policy to ensure you understand how they handle your Personal Information. When you finance or lease your vehicle through a Nissan dealer, you may be informed that your Personal Information may be shared with Nissan and other third parties.

**12\. Contact Us**

**Customer Service:**  
Nissan Canada Inc.  
Customer Information Centre  
5290 Orbitor Drive  
Mississauga, ON L4W 4Z5

Toll Free Number: [1-800-387-0122](tel:1-800-387-0122)  
Fax: 1-844-713-3374  
Email: [information.centre@nissancanada.com](mailto:information.centre@nissancanada.com)

Nissan Canada Financial Service Inc.  
Client Relations Department  
5290 Orbitor Drive  
Mississauga, ON L4W 4Z5

Nissan Canada Financial Service Inc.  
Client Relations Department  
5290 Orbitor Drive  
Mississauga, ON L4W 4Z5

Western Canada: [1-800-268-0754](tel:1-800-268-0754)  
Eastern Canada: [1-800-268-6499](tel:1-800-268-6499)  
Fax: 1-800-256-0835  
Email: [ncfcustomer.service@nissancanada.com](mailto:ncfcustomer.service@nissancanada.com)

**Privacy Officer:**  
Nissan Canada Inc.  
5290 Orbitor Drive  
Mississauga, ON L4W 4Z5  
Email: [privacy@nissancanada.com](mailto:privacy@nissancanada.com)

Attention: Privacy Officer
